

S.M. SAMEER

Data Engineer

Software Engineer with around 1+ years of experience in building user interactive applications, possess hands-on experience in solving syntactical challenges and scalability problems for different domains. Inclined towards the field of data engineering with a desire to expand my skill sets.

msameer112@gmail.com

B-306, BML Palms, Jamia Masjid Road, M S Palya, Vidyaranyapura Post, Bengaluru - 560097

github.com/shaikksameer

6362410598

in linkedin.com/in/s-m-sameer-68446b135

EDUCATION

COMPUTER ENGINEERING AND DATA SCIENCE

PRESIDENCY UNIVERSITY, BENGALURU, KARNATAKA

08/2018 - 07/2022 7.77 CGPA

12TH STANDARD

Kendriya Vidyalaya NO.1

03/2017 - 06/2018 72.06%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data specialist

Futurense Technologies

12/2022 - Present Bangalore, Karnataka Tools Used: SQL, Python, Git, AWS Cloud, Hive, Hadoop, Databricks, Azure Achievements/Tasks

- Implemented SQL reporting on employee management system to gain insights on building various reporting formats
- Gained an overview of the whole process of **Data Engineering**
- Worked on core services in Azure Cloud under security, compute, storage, database, etc

Junior Automation Engineer Valenta Ai

01/2022 - 11/2022 Bangalore, Karnataka Tools Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, OneReach.ai,Dialog Flow Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on project like creating interactive chatbot for Unicomer Group, have also deployed chatbot in various form of channels (WhatsApp, RWC, Facebook, etc)
- Enhanced several features that reduced the manual intervention by automating the process which helped to minimize the error rate by 80%
- Worked on maintaining a database containing feedback, conversations, and interests of individuals

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Credit Card Analytic (03/2023 - 03/2023)

- Successfully built a complete data pipeline for analyzing credit card data using Snowflake and MongoDB and generated reports in Dashboard
- Ingested data from local to snowflake (close to 300,000 records) using snowsql and in MongoDB using mongo shell(mongoimport)
- Using SQL query in Snowflake analyzed data and mongo command in MongoDB shell
- Created reports by using the inbuilt dashboard of the snowflake and in MongoDB exported (mongoexport) the solution in the format of CSV file and used Power BI for building dashboard

PlayerTracker: Building a Comprehensive Database for Tracking Player (09/2020 - 10/2020)

- Created a python-interface, with a menu-driven to automate the process of admin users
- Collected and stored the duration using MySQL database and built 3 triggers to streamline the process inserting data, and trigger to make decision on the subscription status
- Worked on Visualization palette to show the usage of the package and total hours played by the user using Matplotlib

HealthCare Management (06/2022 - 07/2022)

- Developed over 15+ stored routines with features such as obtaining pharmacy information for particular medications, determining the count of patients treated for specific diseases in a given city and etc
- Utilized SQL Joins , Aggregate Functions , and Window Functions to extract meaningful insights from the data
- Constructed 3 triggers to monitor and store the date and time of when a new city or state is added to the database, and to track all transactions that involve updating inventory

CERTIFICATES

Supervised Learning with scikit-learn (06/2020 - 07/2020)

Data Camp

Applied Plotting, Charting & Data Representation in Python (07/2020 - 08/2020)

coursera.org /verif y/YKG BBKH G C BM W